hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft after
last episode i did say i was a bit
frustrated with how the bass was going
but now that i have a bit of breathing
room pardon the pun
i am pretty happy with how this is going
so i'm actually going to make this a bit
of a terrarium so as you can see i've
added loads of dirt and i'm going to
continue doing that and i've actually
got myself a couple of grass blocks so
i'm going to leave this
to spread throughout the whole thing and
then it should look really nice and
green one thing that i do want to do is
change this glass to match this glass
which means a lot of dye needs to be
acquired so it might have to be
mismatched for a while and i've also got
myself some proper enchanted gear so i
should take
a bit more of a beating before i go down
and lose all my stuff and rage quit over
and over and over again so i've got
protection and braking and thorns fire
protection and then i ran out of levels
and i've got loads of good gear now i
think i'm actually starting to get
somewhere and it's starting to feel
really really good what i also thought i
would do
is
not make the front of the ship entirely
but maybe just a little bit so i thought
what we could do
is just add the bow of the ship or the
both i don't know what the word is i
don't know these technical terms
so if we line ourselves up
we can make
the front of the ship sort of
come out of the ground just a little bit
so it looks like
it has properly
so it's a proper shipwreck now obviously
in the normal ones there's basically the
whole ship there and it goes up but i
don't have the space for that
so i'm kind of just gonna have to work
with what i've got
i think that's pretty good it looks like
it's connected up i mean to be honest
with you it should sort of go way across
and this does look like the tip but it
almost looks like it's falling in
and we've got more of a complete ship
here and it's just fun to sort of run
around and jump on and that's that's the
main thing i care about the grass is
starting to spread and once the grass
has spread this will be very easy to
just sort of bone meal up and get lots
of grass in it and make it look extra
nice so i'm pretty happy with how this
is going i'm just terrified that
something's gonna spawn and blow it all
up but i think that's a pretty good way
to start and it should look good once
i've got it all lit up outside because i
have actually got my hands on some
pickles somewhere i tell you what this
base needs
this really needs sorting out because it
feels like i've lost my phone
all the time like i'm looking in every
single room everything look at all this
rubbish absolute rubbish i'm looking in
every single chest every single time for
something and i can't believe i'm
looking for where where are my pickles
where where are my pickles
don't you hate it when you've just
misplaced your pickles there they are
there they are
so the way you harvest pickles is you
have to grow them on top of a coral
block which is frustrating and this is
the entrance to my base by the way which
i think is pretty unique this is the
only way in or out apart from the air
column over there so if you go in you
start swimming and you literally swim
out of the bottle which is so cool so
let's have a look at this base from the
outside
it doesn't look too bad but the mixture
of glass is really messing it up a
little bit
you can see already how the pickles have
made a big big difference so if i just
place a few more the base should look
really really cool
is that a trident is it there's a
trident fella
where is he
i can't see him
i see the trident but i don't see the
trident guy where is he where's this
drowned because i want these tridents he
must be over here somewhere
right let's go for him
one two
get out of here
ah
[Laughter]
oh it was the thorns oh okay i'm just
okay i'm laughing for no reason i
thought
i thought that it was uh that he threw
the trident at me it bounced off my head
and killed it but it was the thorns on
my armor that that did that
oh my goodness that is so funny
it look that looks hilarious so the plan
today is to build a conduit and i have a
really funny design to use
but
i need a lot of dark prismarine to do it
now i'm going to enlist the help of
someone far more qualified than i am
to make to make the journey to the sea
temple with me to grab all this stuff so
we're actually going to head over to
xi zuma void's base and see if he'll
help me with
with with the whole getting the dark
prismarine thing
as you can tell i'm not particularly
adept at
getting anything in this game and i
actually have a quick travel to his base
because my portal is not synced up
there's so many portals there's one here
there's one over there there's one just
round the corner and there's one over
there and pretty much if i go in any of
them they end up in someone else's base
so i need to
i need to make a better portal to sync
up with my location but if i head back
in exactly the same portal i just went
into
i end up in xyzuma's base
whoa
i love how fast these go oh there he
[Music]
yeah fancy seeing you here neighbor so
this is xyzuma void he does a lot of
technical minecraft stuff and
hermitcraft stuff how did you say my
name uh zuma
you said i could have sworn you said
ex-izuma no
no
uh back in the day i was once known as
shashwanbam
and now you're known as turtle bro
oh yeah this season i changed my skin
i'm now turtleman
so this is this is
zuma's base this is what you've got
going so far i would not call this my
base this is me getting started with
no care for building anything that looks
interesting right this is just getting
the trees getting the plants putting it
all in one place this is how i should
have done it i went heavy on the
building and realized i don't have
anything to build with i had this idea
to create a
really funny underwater conduit just so
that because out where i am in my base
it is a pain but as soon as i don't want
that
uh as soon it is a pain to do anything
underwater so if i get my hands on a
conduit and i've come up with a really
funny design but i actually need a lot
and i mean a lot of dark prismarine
and i'm definitely not qualified to get
it
how much is a lot by the way i don't
have a specific number
but it's okay it's in the region of
hundreds
i think i think we might be able to help
you with that so a place you would find
it naturally in the wild without having
to craft anything right would be
at an ocean monument yeah and i just so
happen to have conquered one i'm i am
out in the middle of the ocean and i'm
sort of surrounded by many people i feel
a bit claustrophobic so we got biffer
behind me i got mumbo in front of me
i've got scar to the left of me you to
the right yeah you're at the heart
you're like i am literally yeah i really
am
right so this could get bad because
there might be phantoms at night
they'll be coming for me
uh and there's now guardians everywhere
so dude this is the place where we can
get your dark prismarine um if you stand
on this corner
which corner is it actually it's this
corner and you look downwards you will
see this ocean monument has two
entrances what
okay
that's weird that's very weird it's got
like a bit sticking out there
have you been in the inside yeah it's
this is this is like
you know how the shape isn't like
perfectly symmetrical this is where part
of it would have been facing the other
direction i think that's why it splits
open i don't know it's kind of hard to
describe i wonder what the inside's like
um i haven't explored it a lot i know
there are a couple of messed up rooms
like there's a sponge room that's
exposed to the outside area the best way
to deal with guardians is to run around
a pillar over and over again
thank you for the demonstration i needed
that
it's hilarious isn't it so if you're
ready to go for it we're going to take a
plunge go into the gap down there and
there'll be doors and stuff on the
inside to use all right isn't that
possible i'm ready
right let's go here we go
oh you went oh god there's so many down
here i'm immediately panicking um i hope
you're behind me there we go cool if we
go over here there's loads of doors in
this space
there we are where are you oh my god oh
my god head past the cobble
oh no oh oh no oh no oh no you know
where you're going keep going
way straight ahead
nice
i'm just good i'm just gonna lay down
here for a sec okay
this is it we can just mine the stuff
now um i've blocked it off so that there
are no
pesky guardians okay i think we're gonna
have to do it like this so i'm gonna
have to put a sponge in here
right yeah sponges don't really work as
well as they did
yes because the water can once again
oh another sponge room so we have
successfully found three sponge rooms is
that it's unheard of
it's amazing yeah that's super duper
rare because it's a bugged out one it
may even have more than three um i think
i might jump down here and see what's
going on
ah no too many guardians not enough
are you down there
don't go down there
you only saw you only saw half of it go
around the corner and just take a little
peek oh
i can imagine
oh there's got to be a quicker way to
get rid of that many
all right my man i've got a conduit for
you
thank you
and 45 dark prismarine i've contributed
so much save no savior i don't think
that's gonna be quite enough for what i
have in mind but i think we've hollowed
this place out on the dark prismarine
front and until we've got a farm for
those fellas i don't think i'm going to
get any more
yeah it feels like that um i know there
are probably one or two more places it's
a lot bigger than it feels when you're
inside it right okay so if you if you've
got the time it might be worth having a
look a little bit further
okay i think i'm probably just going to
sail back
yep good luck with your builds and let
me know if you need any more help
so a little bit of time has passed and
you may notice that my voice sounds
rough i basically had to take 24 hours
off because my voice was completely gone
and it's still not back as you can tell
but that meant i had an entire 24 hours
on the hermitcraft server without being
able to record anything so what did i do
i went an annoyed mumbo of course so i
went to his base
i spawned a lot of chickens all over the
island he still didn't notice so i put
the chickens down in his bunker and then
he finally came up i milked his cows and
i scarfed it was brilliant but my voice
has come back for just a minute and i
know i sound really rough but there is a
few things that i really need to do
before i can end this episode so if you
can put up with my harsh voice for just
the rest of this episode that would be
great and then we can get this out
perfectly so what i've done is i've
finished putting together the inside of
this bottle i've only got a few
little bits of glass left to replace
with the stained glass but i'm pretty
happy with how this is look i even added
a custom tree now there's two more
things that i want to do before i end
this episode one is make a conduit but
the first thing i need to do
is
i propose
to start
a server wide game of tag
and
this
is the tag that i'm going to use so i'm
going to write down a bunch of rules in
a rule book
and then we're going to initiate this
game so to begin i will be it and i'm
gonna go and find someone and tag them
and then i'm gonna chuck the rulebook at
them so that they know how to play and
hopefully
this will start a chain of events that
lasts a very long time and i'm pretty
sure this game is going to evolve over
time so let's quickly write down the
rules
so it's called tag you're it
okay so here are the rules that i've
just come up with
the rules of hermitcraft tag one you
must keep the tag in your inventory at
all times that is the key thing of this
you must keep it on you
two if you lose the tag you must replace
it fairly simple three you cannot tag
someone in the same episode you were
tagged for example if i was tagged in
this episode in number three i would
have to wait until number four to tag
someone else
number four you cannot tag the same
person who tagged you that stops it
going backwards and forwards between two
people and five if you tag someone new
to the game you must give them this rule
book otherwise they won't know why you
hit them and ran away
and number six the game can evolve over
time so i think i want to sign this and
we can just write a new rulebook if if
they want to so i think yeah we'll do
that we'll sign it for now
hermitcraft tag volume one
perfect so now all we need to do is find
someone to tag and
i think you all know who i'm gonna go
for because i have a direct access to
their base what's this
four slabs in two by two
exercise zuma i see i don't know what
that means if i'm oh i get the full
block oh yeah this is one of the new
blocks thanks zuma i don't know how you
get this yet but i'm gonna keep this for
later so i think part of the game here
is that you're meant to tag sneakily
they're not supposed to know what's
going on
until it's too late
so
this basically any direction from here
will go directly to mumbo's base which i
personally i think that's hilarious
and also i think it's key that we start
a chain reaction here so
if if i go and tag mumbo for example we
all need to go to his episode that he
gets tagged in and say tag you're it or
something along those lines i'm i'm
hoping over time being it will be the
worst thing possible so i'm hoping that
if you're it people reject you people
don't want to be near you i think it'd
be really really funny like if it just
gets out of hand i don't know how far
this is gonna go but i really hope it
does go somewhere and gets really crazy
all right i'm at mumbo's base whether
he's here or not i'm not entirely sure
but i need to do this very quickly i
need to hit him with this throw both of
these items
or throw both of these items like that
and then scarf her away as soon as
possible so that
he can work it out
this should be really really funny there
he is he's down there in his bunker
let's go down
look at all the chickens
i think he's afk
i really only want to tag him if he's
not afk
okay slight change of plan
so mumbo is
genuinely afk
but dark mc is on his way here
and so he's not afk and i'm going to
i'm going to tag him instead since mumbo
is genuinely just not here and i don't
want him to miss it because knowing him
it'll go in his inventory and he will
miss it
so doc is going to be the officially
he's going to officially be the first
person that gets tagged in this game the
chickens are giving me away
i don't think he knows where mumbo's
bunker is
well since we're waiting a while might
as well continue
what i was doing
in a twist of events
doc went and thought that was mumbo's
base so he swam down there trying to get
in
died his stuff was everywhere little did
he know i was right here so he said oh
i'm gonna lose my stuff and i was like
oh i can get it and then i've put his
stuff here
and now
okay so not only am i pointing him to
mumbo's base which is where he wanted to
go anyway to pick up a slime ball i've
given him his stuff back and i will be
waiting down there for him because mumbo
for some reason is still afk what are
you doing what are you doing the amount
of chickens in here is crazy i don't
think i'm ever going to stop either
just the more chickens there are the
more eggs that they're laying the more i
pick up the more i use them the more
chickens there are and it keeps
away
i should not sing when my voice is
terrible
doc is taking forever
oh he's finally here it took him about
half an hour
name tag is ready
book ready
gladiators ready
he must be getting his stuff back and
then he's going to come down here
and then we're going to tag him and then
we're going to scarf her away meanwhile
mumbo has just been standing there the
whole time while all this action's been
going on come on doc how hard is it
honestly
the island is small
he's still looking around for it
he's found it
oh he's finally found it
oh there we go
okay he has no idea we're here he has no
idea
okay we got to be very good about this
run
[Laughter]
okay we did it oh my goodness
oh my goodness
all the time mumbo's been standing there
oh
oh brilliant
now we've got to make our escape he
didn't even say anything
the game has officially begun so that's
it hermitcraft game of tag is now
underway
and now the last thing that i want to do
before we leave
is make a conduit so i can swim around
here forever exile zoomer or zoomer was
more than kind enough to give me a very
very valuable conduit and i actually
spent because i had 24 hours on the
hermitcraft without being able to speak
i arranged all my chests so it is pretty
neat and tidy around here now so we
actually managed to get
just under three stacks of dark
prismarine now i know that's not enough
for what i want to make and i'm gonna
make it just over there so it should
reach all the way in here
and around the area where i'm going to
end up building but there's a very
specific shape i want to build for this
and 10
green points to whoever can tell me what
it is i'm going to make so we're going
to time lapse this now
let's get into it
this is going to be an extremely speedy
time lapse because i had to keep going
up for air because i didn't know exactly
where the conduit was going to be so i'm
not going to tell you what it is but
hopefully you can guess what it is i was
making and it took a surprisingly low
amount of time about 20 minutes to make
this
and i am really happy with this and i
will be making an entire conduit design
video very soon
and there it is the final product
if you didn't know and you didn't get
the the 10 green points this is
squidward's house from spongebob
squarepants and i think it's a pretty
good recreation and i finally have the
conduit power which means i no longer
have to worry about my bubbles going
down and drowning around here and i
think i surrounded it enough
to
give it a good amount of distance
between me and the conduit the other
thing that i want to mention is i used
every single prismarine brick
to
the block there is not a single one left
i had to be very conservative which is
why i made it on this mountain here so
that i could
minimize the amount that i had to use
even though it kind of stuck up above
and i even made the ears a bit smaller i
really had to be very clever with how i
placed them and i managed to make it
despite only having three stacks of the
blocks i think this is a pretty good
recreation and i hope that everyone that
finds this knows what it is and has a
good little giggle about it but i have
seen a few people say that i haven't
built anything futuristic yet and that's
true i haven't
and this isn't futuristic this isn't
futuristic but i am slowly gathering the
resources to be able to build my grand
futuristic base this is just to get me
started guys but you know what i'm like
i can't just live in a dirt hut i have
to make something special so give me
enough time i will gather the stuff i
need and we will make something extra
epic these last few blocks are bothering
me but i will have to fix those another
time oh my goodness i love this so much
so this has been a really good and
almost bad episode bad because i got
really rather ill and couldn't record
but a lot of stuff has happened because
most of this was recorded over three
days so the ship in the bottle is pretty
much done and decorated my chests are
all organized we have started the game
of tag and doc is the first person to be
tagged we messed around with mumbo jumbo
and made our little appearance as we
seem to always do and i sent him
chickens galore in his base along with
singing him a little afk song it has
been a particularly good episode as we
finally have our conduit unfortunately
you've had to put up with my horrible
horrible voice for the second half of
this video so i do apologize for that i
am on the mend as you can probably tell
i'm starting to sound a little bit
better and hopefully
i will be good as new by the next
episode so that's it for me everyone
thank you very much for watching i hope
you enjoyed this episode of hermitcraft
let me know all your thoughts and
comments and stuff and likes etc down
below and good
bye
i'm so ill